<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tableau | [ Sustainability &#43; Data ] · Science</title>
    <link>/tag/tableau/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tableau</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2020 Edgar Rodríguez-Huerta</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo-edgarodriguez.png</url>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>/tag/tableau/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 effect in mortality rates in Mexico</title>
      <link>/post/covid-19-mx-deaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/covid-19-mx-deaths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the effect of &lt;strong&gt;COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt; on the death rate in &lt;strong&gt;Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;? 
Is it true that deaths are classified with different causes to avoid an increase the number of cases?
I analyzed the information from the Epidemiological and Statistical System of Deaths (SEED) from 1998 to September 2020 to determine the increase in the mortality rate vs. the historical data.
Although there are several States with important delays in updating information &lt;em&gt;(especially: OAXACA, MICHOACÁN, GUERRERO, PUEBLA, JALISCO)&lt;/em&gt;, in June 2020 the rate increased to almost 70 deaths per 100,000 inhabitants (30%). &lt;strong&gt;Mexico City&lt;/strong&gt; almost tripled its rate (160 deaths per 100,000 inhabitants) compared to the same period, which represented that 1 of each 4 deaths in Mexico City is due to COVID-19. Until June 30, 2020[^fn1], COVID-19 caused 11% of total deaths in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 2,300 deaths were detected with causes related to COVID-19, classified with another cause, mainly &lt;strong&gt;J129 &amp;lsquo;Viral Pneumonia, Unspecified&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; with around 300 more cases compared to the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[^fn1] It was defined until June 2020 due to the delay in the SEED data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see the complete analysis, and how each State goes, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/DefuncionesCOVID19-Mexico/EfectoCOVID?:language=en&amp;amp;:display_count=y&amp;amp;:origin=viz_share_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here is the interactive (in Spanish)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./figure1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobility in Mexico after COVID-19</title>
      <link>/post/covid-19-mx-mobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/covid-19-mx-mobility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mobility has changed due to COVID-19. In Mexico, it decreased significantly in mid-March 9, but just a month later we observed a gradual recovery, especially in trips to workplaces.
In September 2020, mobility to workplaces has remained stable with -24%. However, mobility to parks and shopping centers increased 30% compared to last month, reaching the levels of March 2020. The increase in mobility may indicate a second significant wave and before the end of the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the relationship between mobility and the contagion rate in each region?
Why do states with the greatest reduction in mobility have high numbers of infections?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, all trips have decreased compared to the beginning of the year, but on weekends the reduction is less. What accounts for this difference?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see the complete analysis, and how each State goes, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/views/AnlisisdemovilidadMxico/MovilidadMxico?:language=en&amp;amp;:display_count=y&amp;amp;:origin=viz_share_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here is the interactive (in Spanish)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./figure1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data cleaning with Tableau Prep</title>
      <link>/post/tableau-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tableau-prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data preparation tools create dynamic and reproducible data flow diagrams at multiple scales, helping to reduce work times. In my case, I cut my time in half. 
This is a diagram that I generated with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tableau.com/products/prep&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tableau Prep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in July 2020 to process data on historical deaths in Mexico, and the effect that COVID-19 has had on other causes of deaths. 
Data flow diagrams create a dynamic and easy-to-use experience that reduce worktime and encourage to reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
