<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nexus WEFL | [ Sustainability &#43; Data ] · Science</title>
    <link>/site/tag/nexus-wefl/</link>
      <atom:link href="/site/tag/nexus-wefl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Nexus WEFL</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2020 Edgar Rodríguez-Huerta</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/site/media/logo-edgarodriguez.png</url>
      <title>Nexus WEFL</title>
      <link>/site/tag/nexus-wefl/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Societal Metabolism</title>
      <link>/site/project/water-societal-metabolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/site/project/water-societal-metabolism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main objectives of this project are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1)	Diagnose water consumption based on the metabolic pattern existing in the socio-economic system of the Yucatan Peninsula, Mexico; providing integrated information on the flows of water consumption at different productive and domestic levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2)	Generate a tool based on the Multi-Scale Integrated Analysis of Societal and Ecosystem Metabolism (MuSIASEM) methodology that allows simulating different future scenarios to verify its viability and convenience in relation to the consumption of water resources with the limits established by the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(3)	Create geo-referenced data on the effect of climate change in the region, which will help in the decision-making process on the definition of development plans at the regional level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the WMR it is possible to know how compatible the growth is expected for the region with sustainable water management. In other words, if the appropriation of water prevents the structures of the eco-systemic services from being maintained (within the biophysical limits of the recharge without affecting the natural discharge), then the social metabolic pattern will not be feasible in the long term; so, it will not be sustainable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, an estimation of water supply is made based on a monthly water balance model using historical data from 1961-2000 (considering that groundwater is the main source of water in the region). Later, the same water balance model is applied to the bioclimatic output data (precipitation and temperature) from four downscaled General Circulation Models (GCM), and a reliability ensemble averaging (REA), in the near horizon (2015-2039); in order to compare the effect on climate change on groundwater recharge in the region. On the other hand, different scenarios of water demand based are generated on MuSIASEM methodology and water metabolic patterns (WMR), which considers the socio-economic structure of our case study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the societal metabolism perspective and sustainable yield, if demand exceeds supply (including discharge to streams and wetlands) then water use is unsustainable. Our results estimate groundwater recharge of 118 ± 33 mm·year–1 (around 10 % of precipitation) in the historical period, and a decrease around of 20 % of groundwater recharge caused by climate change (less precipitation and higher temperature) which, together with the trend of water use linked to the economic and demographic growth expected, reaches or exceeds the recharge of groundwater in two of four scenarios, compromising the natural discharge, threatening the future socioecological equilibrium of the region&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WMR evolution depends on the characteristics of the sector and its weight within the society and explains how each productive sector has growth in YP, and how this development is related to increasing water use. The analysis provides a new narrative for the relationship between water use and the societal structure, identifying patterns of consumption beyond general averages, ‘per capita’ indicators that hide particularities at a sub-region scale in the YP. Our study describes different consumption patterns across YP, and compares the social and economic characteristics of each state, allowing the personalization of development plans, protection policies, or concrete actions that contribute to groundwater conservation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
